Can we not make a run for it, Doctor?
我们就不能逃跑吗，博士？
No. We wouldn't even reach the ladder.
It's too risky.
不，我们甚至都到不了梯子那里。这太冒险了
What can we do?
我们能做什么？
Play for time. Wait for our chance.
Leave it to me.
拖延时间，等待机会。这交给我吧
Excuse me? May I ask a question?
对不起，我可以问一个问题吗？
Why did you submit yourself to freezing?
你们为什么把自己冷冻起来？
You don't have to answer that,
if you don't want to
你们不一定要回答，如果你们不想的话
To survive.
为了生存
Our history computer
has full details of you.
我们的电脑里有对你的详细描述
Oh? How?
噢？怎样的？
We know of your intelligence.
我们知道你的智慧
Oh. Thank you very much.
哦，非常感谢
Ah, yes. The lunar surface.
啊，是的，月球表面
Our machinery had stopped
我们的机器停了
and our supply of replacements
been depleted.
我们的替代品供应也耗尽了
So that's why you attacked the moonbase.
所以你们就去攻击月球基地
You had destroyed our first planet
你摧毁了我们的第一颗行星
and we were becoming extinct.
我们就逐渐灭绝了
What difference does capturing us make?
You'll still become extinct.
把我们抓起来有什么用？你们还是会灭绝
We will survive.
我们会活下去
You will become the first
of a new race of Cybermen.
你们会变成第一批新一代赛博人
You will return to Earth
and control it.
你们将回到地球，掌控它
But we're humans. We're not like you.
但我们是人类，跟你们不一样
You will be.
你们会一样的
Oh. No. Keep away!
噢，不要，离我远点！
Keep away!
离远点！
Keep away...!
离远点...
It's very quiet down there.
下面非常安静
Yeah. Too quiet.
是啊，太安静了
- Something must have happened.
- How long they been down?
- 肯定发生什么事情了  - 他们下去多久了？
About an hour.
大概一个小时
That's too long. I'm going down.
那太长了。我下去看看
You are a logician.
你是个逻辑学家
Our race is also logical.
我们种族也是讲求逻辑的
You will be the leader of the new race.
你将是新种族的领袖
You will listen to my proposals, then?
那，你们将会听我的提议啰？
Yes. We will listen.
是的，我们会听
But first you will be altered.
但首先你得被改造
Altered?
改造？
You have fear.
你有恐惧
We will eliminate fear from your brain.
我们将从你的大脑里移除恐惧
Yes. You will be the first.
是的，你将是第一个
And you will be the next.
而你将是下一个
No! No! Aagh!
不，不！啊！
You will be like us.
你将会跟我们一样
To die is unnecessary.
死亡是不必要的
You will be frozen
你们将会被冻结
and placed in our tombs
置入我们的坟墓中
until we are ready to use you.
直到我们准备好使用你们
Your lives will be suspended.
你们的生命将会暂停
Prepare the tombs.
准备好墓室
They really mean it.
They're going to freeze us.
他们来真的, 这是要冰冻我们
- Not me.  - No, they're coming back.
- 对我休想  - 糟, 他们要回来了
Come on, you guys. Run for it!
快点, 伙计们, 跑啊！
Jamie!
Jamie!﻿
Look at that smoke.
看那个烟
(JAMIE) Victoria!
Victoria!﻿
Come on, Mr Parry. Come on, quick!
快啊, Parry 先生, 加油, 快！
The Cybermen! They're right behind us.
赛博人！他们就在我们后面
As soon as the Doctor's up,
close down the hatch!
等博士一上来, 就关闭舱门！
- OK!  - Stand by!
- 好！  - 准备！
Oh! Aagh! He's got my leg!
噢, 啊！他抓住了我的腿！
Doctor, come on!
博士, 加油！
- Come on!  - It's no use.
- 加油！  - 没有用
Jim, close the hatch!
Jim, 关掉舱门！
(CALLUM) Got him!
搞定他了！
(BANGING)
It was horrible. It was so strong!
太可怕了, 它这么强！
It's all right, Victoria.
You're all right now.
没事了, Victoria. 你现在安全了
That was a near thing. Is anyone missing?
刚才太险了, 有谁失踪吗？
Yes. Klieg and Toberman.
They're still down there!
有, Klieg 和 Toberman。他们还在下面!
Don't open it. It may be the Cybermen.
别打开, 可能是赛博人
No. No, it's too soft.
不, 不像, 太轻了
- It must be Toberman and Klieg.
- Are you crazy?
- 肯定是 Toberman 和 Klieg  - 你疯了?
You're right. We can't leave them
down there even if they are killers.
你是对的。我们不能把他们扔在下面, 就算他们是杀人犯
They're both probably frozen solid by now.
他们俩这会儿肯定被完全冻住了
You must let them up. They must be saved.
你必须让他们上来, 必须要救他们
Yes, they're more dangerous
down there than up here.
是的, 下面比上面这里危险得多
What? OK. Jim?
什么？好．Jim？
Right.
马上
(KNOCKING)
Okey. Let her go.
好， 打开它
Excuse me, please.
对不起，让让
Shut it! Shut it quick!
关上！快关上！
- Where's Toberman?  - They've got him.
- Toberman 在哪里？  - 他们抓住他了
You still think you can form an alliance
with the Cybermen, Mr Klieg?
你还觉得你能跟赛博人结成联盟吗，Klieg先生？
If only I'd been in a stronger position
to bargain with them.
我要是在一个更有利的位置, 就可以和他们谈条件了
You must be out of your mind, Klieg
你肯定是脑子进水了， Klieg
You're not in any position
to bargain with anybody right now.
你现在没有同任何人谈条件的资本
What are we going to do with them?
我们打算拿他们怎么样？
I'd feel much happier
if they weren't in here.
如果他们不在这里, 我会高兴得多
What about the testing room?
There's only one door. They can't get out.
测试室怎么样？它只有一个门，他们出不去
Good idea. They'll be quite safe in there.
好主意。他们在那里面比较安全
- Callum!  - Right.
- Callum!  - 好
Mr Klieg?
Klieg 先生？
Miss Kaftan.
Kaftan 小姐
These humanoids are not like us.
这些人类跟我们不一样
They still have fear.
他们还是有恐惧感
Place the Cybermats on the runway.
把赛博鼠放到轨道上
Cybermats will attack.
赛博鼠将发起攻击
Oh!
呵！
I'm on your side, remember?
我是你这边的, 记得吗？
Hey, why didn't you wake me?
嘿, 你为什么不叫醒我？
I should have been on watch
half an hour ago.
在半小时前就应该轮到我放哨了
- I thought you should rest.  - Why me?
- 我觉得你应该多休息  - 为什么是我?
No reason really.
没什么原因
Oh, I think I know.
Was it because I'm...?
噢, 我想我知道了．是不是因为我...？
Well, if you are 450 years old,
you need a great deal of sleep.
嗯, 如果你已经450岁了, 你需要睡很多觉
Well, that's very considerate of you, Victoria,
啊, 你真能体谅人, Victoria
but, between you and me,
I'm really quite lively actually -
但, 别告诉别人啊, 我其实很有生命力的 -
all things being considered.
不管从哪方面来说
Are you happy with us, Victoria?
你跟我们在一起快乐吗, Victoria？
Yes, I am.
嗯, 是的
At least, I would be if my father were here.
至少, 如果我父亲也在这里我会更快乐
Yes, I know. I know.
是的, 我知道，我知道
I wonder what he'd thought
if he could see me now.
我想知道, 如果他现在能见到我, 他会怎么想
You miss him very much, don't you?
你非常想念他, 是不是？
It's only when I close my eyes...
嗯, 每当我闭上眼睛
I can still see him standing there.
我都能看到他站在那里
Before those horrible
Dalek creatures came to the house.
在那些 Dalek 怪物来到我们屋之前
He was a very kind man.
他是一个很善良的人
I shall never forget him. Never.
我永远也不会忘记他, 永远
No, of course you won't.
不会, 你当然不会的
But, you know, the memory of him
won't always be a sad one.
但是, 你知道吗, 对他的记忆并不会总是悲伤的
I think it will.
我觉得会的
You can't understand, being so ancient.
你不会明白了, 你这么古老
- Eh?  - I mean old.
- 嗯？  - 我是说年长
You probably can't remember your family.
你可能都不记得你的家庭了
Oh, yes, I can when I want to.
哦, 记得, 当我想要想起，就能
That's the point.
就是这个意思
I have to really want to
bring them back in front of my eyes.
我只是必须得在脑海里把他们带到我的眼前
The rest of the time
they sleep in my mind and I forget.
其它时候他们沉睡在我的意识里, 我就忘记了
And so will you. Oh, yes, you will.
你也会这样的．噢, 是的, 你也会的
You'll find there's so much else
to think about, to remember.
你会发现有太多其它的事情要去考虑, 去记忆
Our lives are different to anybody else's.
我们每个人的生命跟其他任何一个人都不同的
That's the exciting thing.
这是最让人激动的地方
There's nobody in the universe
can do what we're doing.
宇宙中没有谁能做我们在做的事情
You must get some sleep,
你必须去睡一会儿了
and let this poor old man stay awake.
让这个可怜的老人醒着吧
Jamie, Victoria, Callum, wake up!
Jamie, Victoria, Callum, 醒醒！
- Wake up!  - What is it?
- 醒醒！  - 怎么了？
Callum. Callum.
Callum. Callum.﻿
(VICTORIA) Those terrible things.
这些可怕的东西
Don't move, Callum. Don't move.
别动, Callum, 别动
Get back to the controls, all of you.
回到开关那边去, 你们全部
Steady. Don't make any sudden movements.
Parry, wake up.
慢点，别陡然乱动。Parry, 醒醒
Don't panic. Come back with us. Steady.
别惊慌, 到我们这边来, 慢点
We'll all go in the other room
and lock them out.
我们全部去另外那个房间, 把它们关在外面
Aagh!
啊！
Let's get out of here.
我们离开这里
The main doors.
大门
No!
不要！
Oh! Oh, Doctor, we're trapped!
噢！噢, 博士, 我们被困住了！
Back against the controls, everybody.
背靠控制台, 所有人
Here.
这里
Give me a hand, quick.
帮我一把, 快
Lay this down on the ground. Come on!
把这个铺设在地板上, 快点
- Doctor?  - Come on!
- 博士？  - 快点！
Let's blast the filthy things!
我们轰掉这些丑恶的东西！
You're wasting your time.
There are too many of them! Come back!
你是在浪费自己的时间．它们太多了, 回来！
- There you are. You see?
- What are those creatures?
- 这下好了，看到了吧？ - 那些怪物是什么？
Well, they're...
嗯, 它们是...
They're a form of metallic life.
它们是一种金属生命形式
They home on human brainwaves, and attack.
它们朝人类脑电波前进, 实施攻击
Urgh!
呃！
Are they safe now?
现在它们没危险了吗？
Quite safe now. The power cable
generated an electrical field
现在相当安全了．这根电缆产生了一个电场
that confused their tiny metal minds.
搅乱了它们那金属的小脑袋
You might say that they've had
a complete metal breakdown.
你可以说它们完全是“金属崩溃”了
(博士在这里借用了 metal breakdown
与 mental breakdown (精神崩溃)发音相近的特点)
- Ooh.  - I'm so sorry, Jamie.
- 哦   - 真的很抱歉, Jamie
What about Klieg and Kaftan?
They've probably been attacked as well.
Klieg 和 Kaften 怎么样了？他们很可能也一样被攻击了
- The testing room.
- Come on. Mind your feet.
- 测试室  - 快点, 小心脚下
Most ingenious, Doctor.
真是聪明啊, 博士
Now let's see what you can do against this.
现在我们来看看你怎么对付这个
Watch out, Doctor!
小心, 博士！